Remember...
牢记
What do I do with him now?
我现在该怎么办？
I won't let you die before telling me why you tried to kill me.
在你告诉我为什么要杀我之前不会让你死的
Conscience.
良心
You won't look me in the eye?
你不能正视我吗？
Because you left that cushy job and went and became a cop!
因为你离开了那份轻松的工作而去当了警察！
It was ten years ago. A family came
十年前，一户人家
and moved in to that house on the hill.
搬进山上那间房子
There were a few burglaries.
发生几起盗窃案
Everybody blamed the new family.
每个人都怪罪新来的人家
They burned the house down.
他们把房子烧了
I'm here now. Looking for a job...
我现在在这里找工作
Here. Here's my resumé.
这是我的简历
- Do you know Agah Beyoglu? - He's my father.
-你认识Agah Beyoglu吗？-他是我父亲
Ates, aren't you afraid at all that the murderer will target you?
Ates，你不担心凶手会把你当作目标吗？
Just like he has his eyes on me,
就像他看着我一样
I have my eyes on the perimeter of my house.
我也在我家周围布置了眼线
I'm going to get that killer.
我要抓到那个凶手
Wherever he runs to. Wherever he hides. I'm going to find him, and arrest him.
无论他跑到哪里，我都会找到他并逮捕他
TODAY IS NEVRA'S BIRTHDAY I GOT HER A BIRTHDAY PRESENT
今天是Nevra的生日，我给她准备了一份礼物
You've grown older, too.
你也变老了
Hi there, Nazif. Remember me?
嗨  Nazif还记得我吗？
It's Agah.
我是Agah
From Kambura.
来自Kambura
Nazif?
Nazif?
Hello, Nazif.
你好，Nazif
How are you doing, Nazif?
Nazif，你好吗？
Pause it. He's here.
暂停，在这里
He jumped over the back fence.
他跳过了后篱笆
What's that?
那是什么？
What is he wearing?
他穿的是什么？
Is it supposed to be a rabbit?
是兔子吗？
No. It's a cat.
不，是猫
See its whiskers?
看到它的胡须吗？
A white cat.
一只白猫
00:53.
00:53
When did you leave the nightclub?
你什么时候离开夜总会的？
Around 01:30.
大约01:30
I was just leaving when you called. I'm usually done by 01:00.
你打给我的时候我正要走  我通常在01:00之前离开
He was keeping tabs on you.
他一直在监视你
There's a road that comes in through the woods, right?
有一条路穿过树林，对不对？
Yes.
是
Since he couldn't have taken a cab in that costume...
由于他不可能穿着那套服装上出租车
With a corpse in tow, to boot.
当然也不能带尸体过来
He drove his own car here. Had the corpse with him the whole way.
他带着尸体自己开车来这里
There must be a camera recording that road.
一定有一部摄像机拍摄那条路
We'll see.
我们看一下
He's a lunatic.
他是疯子
Who are you?
你是谁？
Who?
谁？
What's he doing?
他在做什么？
You've left the body there. Leave.
你把尸体留在那里
One: Take a red pen.
一：拿一支红笔
Two:
二：
Kill Nazif.
杀死Nazif
Three:
三：
Don't forget the oud.
不要忘记
Take a red pen, kill Nazif,
拿一支红笔，杀死Nazif，
If Nazif isn't home,
如果纳粹不在家
spare his life.
就饶他一命
Yes.
是
Why did he want to make sure that it sank?
为什么他想确保它沉下去？
- It's a surprise. - What surprise?
-惊喜 -什么惊喜？
He wanted it to be a surprise.
他希望这是一个惊喜
Right. I'm sorry. I didn't know it was your birthday.
对不起，我不知道那是你的生日
Of course not.
没事
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
Happy birthday to me.
祝我生日快乐
What is he doing?
他在做什么？
Resting.
休息
Not a care in the world. Just wants to lie down for a bit.
不关心其他事  只是想躺一会
I'm back.
我回家了
Whom do you think the corpse belongs to, Nevra?
你认为那具尸体是谁的，Nevra？
Since it's a present...
既然是礼物
It must be someone I've been looking for.
一定是我一直在寻找的人
What do we do now?
我们现在干什么？
I'll call the station.
我给局里打电话
The Crime Scene Unit will arrive.
犯罪现场小组很快就来
They'll go through this footage, find out that I spent the night here,
他们会看完这段录像，发现我在这里过夜
and start avoiding me like the plague.
开始像躲瘟疫一样躲开我
Then they'll ask both you and I thousands of questions.
然后他们会问我们无数问题
And finally, they'll take me off the case.
最后，他们会让我离开这个案子
Followed by my resignation.
并且让我辞职
Or...
或者
None of that will come to pass.
这些都不会发生
You'll delete the footage I'm in.
你删掉有我的镜头
I'll rip those stickers off the balloon.
我将那些贴纸从气球上撕下来
No one will find out that this was meant as a present to me.
没有人会发现这是送给我的礼物
You'll call 155,
你给155打电话
and I'll lie to everyone's faces.
我会骗过大家
Then another lie, then another.
一个接一个的谎言
I'll lie so much that I'll forget to remember them,
谎言太多最后我都记不清了
and I'll be found out sooner or later.
最终我还是会被发现
They'll take me off the case, and I'll probably resign.
他们会对我感到失望，很可能将我辞退
Which one sounds better to you?
哪个听起来对你更好？
- Which one should we go with? - Nevra...
-我们应该选哪个方案？- Nevra...
I say to myself sometimes...
我有时对自己说
I say...
我说
What if I'd never decided to become a cop?
如果我从未决定要做警察怎么办？
What if I never did?
如果我没做过该怎么办？
Would he be committing these murders,
他会犯这些谋杀罪吗，
or are all these people dying just because I chose to be a cop?
还是因为我选择当警察才导致这些人死亡？
See, there you are.
看，你在那
He's still here.
他还在这里
I don't believe it.
我不相信
I'm letting you into the house, and he's still here.
我让你进屋的时候他还在这里
He forgot the bag.
他忘了拿包
KILLER OR VICTIM?
是杀手还是受害者？
That's why he left it here.
这就是为什么他把它留在这里
Can you zoom it?
你可以放大吗？
Can you zoom into the newspaper?
你可以放大报纸吗？
REMEMBER. REMEMBER.
记住……
Remember?
记住？
Remember what?
记住什么？
Is it meant for you?
是给你的吗
Does it mean anything to you?
对你来说有什么特殊含义吗？
It means only one thing.
这意味着只有一件事
It's not the bag that he forgot. He forgot to tell me to remember.
他不是忘了拿包  他是忘了告诉我要记住
- Nevra... - Yes?
-Nevra...-怎么？
- Are you sure? - I am now, Ates.
-确定吗？-现在确定了
They're being killed because I'm a cop.
他们被杀是因为我是警察
And whatever it is that he wants me to remember,
不论他要我记住什么
they'll keep dying until I remember it.
他会一直杀人，直到我记住为止
Connect me to the Crime Scene Unit.
请帮我接通犯罪现场调查组
Where are you off to? It's still early.
你要去哪里？还早呢
I got some pastries. Let's have breakfast.
我买了一些糕点  让我们吃早餐
I can't, dad. I got a job. I have to leave.
不行  爸爸  我要去上班了
- What job? Your old one? - No. I'll tell you about it later.
-什么工作？你之前的工作吗？-不，我晚点再告诉您
- I'm off. - Good luck.
-我走了-祝你好运
- Dad... - Yeah?
-爸爸  -嗯？
Let's go out to dinner tonight.
今晚出去吃饭吧
There's food in the fridge.
冰箱里还有吃的
I know, not like that.
我知道
I want to celebrate the new job.
我想庆祝新工作
But I have errands to run.
但是我有事要做
What errands do you have other than those crosswords?
除了那些填字游戏，你还有什么事？
Be home by eight and we'll leave together.
八点钟回家，我们一起去吃饭
School's started as well, huh?
要去上学了吧？
- I don't remember how to tie it. - I'll do it.
-我不记得该怎么系了-我来吧
Hold these.
拿着这个
And this.
还有这个
- Is she from school? - Who?
-她在学校吗？-谁？
Your girl. What was her name?
你的女朋友  她叫什么名字？
- Suveyda. - Suveyda. That's it.
-Suveyda  - Suveyda  对了
Do you know what the name means?
你知道这个名字的意思吗？
- No. Aren't you done yet? - Patience.
-还没好吗  -耐心
You never wondered what her name meant?
你就不想知道她的名字是什么意思吗？
I don't think names hold any meaning.
我认为名字没有任何意义
- Why? - Because we don't choose our own name.
-为什么？-因为名字不是我们自己选的
Each person
据说每个人
has a black mark on their heart when they're born, they say.
出生时心脏上都有黑色的印记
Once they find their calling in life,
一旦他们找到自己的人生使命
only then does the mark fade away.
黑色的印记才会消失
Suveyda is what that mark is called.
Suveyda就是那个黑色的印记的名字
It does have another meaning, but it escapes me.
还有另一种含义，但我不记得了
- Let's forget about the tie. - Hold on! Hold on!
-算了  不打领带了  -等等！等等！
I'm going to remember it.
让我想一想
It means sin. A hidden sin.
意味着罪恶
The sin people hide in their chests.
藏在心中的罪恶
A deep, hidden sin.
深藏的罪恶
Do you have a hidden sin in there?
你那里有深藏的罪过吗？
I do.
我有
- It's Suveyda. - Right. Of course.
-是Suveyda  -是的  当然了
- How about in yours? - Of course. In spades.
-你呢？-当然了  有很多
There you go.
那就是了
You're ready to go.
你准备好了
- Thanks. - No problem.
-谢谢-没问题
Good luck.
祝好运
Good job, Nevra!
辛苦了，Nevra！
You finally caught the murderer!
您终于抓住了凶手！
You should get a medal or something.
您应该获得奖杯之类的东西
He came to you while you were asleep.
你睡着时他来找你
I guess it's a matter of where you sleep.
我想这跟你睡觉的地方有关
You need to sleep in the right bed for him to come to you.
你需要睡在正确的床上，他才能来找你
You got him delivered.
你收到了一个尸体快递
Delivered to your address.
送货到家
Great! This is great!
太好了！太好了！
You'll pay for that, Nevra!
Nevra！你会为此付出代价
You'll pay for that!
你会为此付出代价！
Back to work!
回去工作！
Are you sick in the head or something?
你脑子有问题吗？
Not only do you try to belittle her in front of everyone at the scene,
你不仅在所有人面前侮辱她
and you do this! You're making a formal complaint?
然后还要投诉她？
You deserved worse than you got!
你本来就是活该啊！
- But sir... - Shut the fuck up!
-但是，先生  -闭嘴！
Get back to work!
回去工作！
So... Dear Ates Arbay. Let's get down to business.
Ates Arbay 让我们谈一谈
Who is your source for all these articles,
这些文章的来源是谁
and what do you give them in return?
你给他们什么回报呢？
I don't give anyone anything.
我什么都不给
I have sources,
我有消息源
and I don't have to tell you who they are.
而且我也不必告诉你他们是谁
Sources...
资料来源
I see. Alright.
我明白了
You see, Ates Arbay, this is dangerous business.
你看  Ates Arbay  这是很危险的交易
Whoever is selling you the case files
不论是谁向你卖消息
might want something more precious in return very soon.
可能很快就会想要一些更珍贵的东西作为回报
They might get greedy. They might sell you down the river.
他们可能会变得贪婪  甚至可能会出卖你
What did I tell you?
我怎么告诉你的？
Follow her every move.
跟随她的一举一动
Shadow her wherever she goes.
无论她走到哪里都跟着她
I'm not sure you're fully aware.
我不确定你是否真的听明白了
If you'd done your job, we'd have the killer by now!
如果你做到了，我们现在就已经抓到凶手了
Sir, may I please speak?
长官，我可以说话了吗？
Go ahead, speak.
快说
She went over to her mom's place last night.
昨晚她去了妈妈的家
Anıl was on her. He called me to ask what he should do.
Anıl在盯着她，他给我打电话请假
- His son was sick, so I let him go home. - Great fucking decision!
-他的儿子病了，所以我让他回家  -真尼玛伟大
You're off the fucking case, alright?
你不用再跟这个案子了，明白吗？
Sefa will handle it now.
Sefa会接手
And take that complaint and stick it up your ass!
带着你的投诉滚蛋吧！
- Welcome. - Shut up.
-欢迎  -闭嘴
Why are you mad at me? I'm on your side.
你为什么对我生气？我们是同一战线的
I told you to shut up.
我叫你闭嘴
- Why am I here? - Don't speak unless spoken to.
-我为什么在这里？-不要说话
I'm the victim here.
我是受害者
The killer came into my home and left a body in my garden.
凶手来到我家，在我的花园里留下了尸体
Still, here you are, interrogating me. Shouldn't you be out looking for him?
你还在这里审问我  你不应该出去找他吗?
What are you going to do? Hit me?
你要怎么做？打我吗？
Go ahead.
打吧
Hit me.
打我
Ates Arbay.
Ates Arbay
My whole career, I've never touched a hair on anyone's head in this room.
在我的整个职业生涯中，我从来没有碰过这个房间里任何人的一根头发。
But if you know something about the case and are hiding it from us,
但是，如果你对案件有所了解并向我们隐瞒，
then I'll knock you into the middle of next week.
那我就一直揍你直到下周
And one more thing.
还有一件事
You're not on our side, Ates Arbay.
你跟我们不是一条战线的，Ates Arbay
You know what side you're on?
你知道你站在哪一边吗？
The side where desk warriors mess with other people's lives.
在办公桌上搅乱他人生活的一面
That's the side you're on.
那就是你的一面
You know what I call the people on that side?
你知道我管那种人称为什么吗？
I call them jesters.
我称他们为小丑
We don't mess with people's lives here.
我们在这里不给别人添乱
We save their lives instead. You got that?
相反  我们拯救他们的生命  明白了吗？
I understand.
我明白
Do you think he does, as well?
你认为他也是吗？
Get him out of here. Out. Out!
带他出去  滚！
- One red pen, as well. - Of course.
-一支红笔 -当然
- Duct tape. - I've already given you some.
-胶带  -我已经给你了
Another one.
还有一个
- And some sticky note cards. - Post-its?
-还有一些便签卡  -便利贴？
Whatever they're called. Give me some.
不管叫什么  给我拿一些吧
Sit down. Sit!
坐下！
This has to be a joke! It has to be!
这一定是个玩笑！一定是！
- Are you Ates Arbay's source? - No, sir.
-你是Ates Arbay的消息来源吗？-不，先生
- Who is it, then? - I don't know.
-那是谁？-我不知道
- He didn't tell you? - He didn't.
-他没告诉你吗？-他没有
Do you trust that man?
你相信那个男人吗？
It doesn't matter.
无所谓了
There will be a press conference tonight.
今晚将举行新闻发布会
The killer turned out not to be the killer. Everyone's in a frenzy.
我们之前确定的凶手竟然不是凶手，人们一定会抓狂的
I want you at the press conference. Don't go anywhere. Now get out.
我要你出席记者招待会  不要去任何地方  现在出去。
- That's it? - That's it.
-就是这样？ -就是这样
You don't have any other questions?
您没有其他问题吗？
The mistakes you make in your private life is your business.
你在私人生活中犯的错误是你自己的事
Just don't make those same mistakes when you're at work.
只是不要在工作的时候犯同样的错误
Will you take me off the case?
你要把我调离这个案子吗？
Nevra, get out.
Nevra  出去
Wait a second. Whom did this belong to?
等一下  这条线是谁的？
Darn it.
哎呀
See? Red's much better.
看吧  红色好多了
More distinctive.
更具特色
Easier to see.
更醒目
Alright...
好了……
What's this?
这是什么？
KILL
杀
I'll never forget now.
这回就不会忘记了
Good afternoon, Hasan.
下午好，Hasan
Won't you take my order?
你不理我吗？
Selim...
Selim...
- How are you? - Fine, Vural. How about you?
-你好吗  -很好，你呢？
- I'm not great, to be honest. - Why's that?
-老实说，我不是很好  -那是为什么？
You're talking too much...
你话太多了
I hear you've been blabbering.
我听说是你在多嘴
What are you saying?
你在说什么？
Telling people it was haunting your dreams.
告诉别人它萦绕在你的梦中
What use is it, talking to people about your dreams, Selim?
跟别人谈论你的梦想有什么用呢？
Something might happen to you.
你可能会出什么意外
And then, when the cops come and ask them what happened to you,
然后，当警察来问他们你发生了什么事时，
no one might feel inclined to talk.
没有人会说话
It's best if you didn't talk.
最好不要说话
Especially to Nevra.
特别是Nevra
You should really tread lightly.
你真的应该小心行事
Selim!
Selim!
Auntie! Auntie!
阿姨  阿姨
- Let the boys carry those for you. - Thank you, Vural.
-让小伙子们帮你搬那些东西  -谢谢  Vural
- Doing well, I hope? - Doing well.
-希望一切都好  -好
Stop by for some tea sometime.
有空来喝茶
Can I help you with anything?
有什么可以帮您的吗？
I'm fine, thank you so much.
不用了，非常感谢
Say hi to your mom for me, though.
给你妈妈带个好
Of course. You're too kind. Have a nice day.
当然  你太客气了  祝你有美好的一天
What can I get you, brother?
兄弟，我能给你什么？
MISSING SUSPECT
证据不足
VICTIM
受害者
- Now, boys... - Tolga, give me a moment.
-好了……  -Tolga，给我一点时间
Nevra, we already know that these murders have something to do with you.
Nevra，我们已经知道这些谋杀案与你相关
This is not a matter of mistaken identity.
这已经不是重名的问题了
You are the Nevra the victim is alluding you, as you know.
现在你也清楚了，凶手说的Nevra就是你
Since, as a matter of protocol,
因此，根据制度
we don't allow officers to work cases they're personally involved in,
我们不允许警察处理涉及他们自己的案件
I didn't want you to take up the case.
我不想让你继续跟进这个案子
Neither did your superior, Tolga.
你的上司也不想
Suspecting that the murderer wasn't stopping anytime soon,
假设凶手近期不会停止杀人
I asked Tolga for a favor.
我请Tolga帮了个忙
I asked him to keep you on this case.
我请他让你继续处理这个案子
Because you were the only connection to the killer that we could find.
因为你是我们唯一与凶手有关联的人
And you still are.
你仍然是
It was now Tolga's turn to ask me for a favor.
现在轮到托尔加要我帮个忙了
He asked me to share all this with you.
他让我和你说这些事情
But I refused.
但是我拒绝了
Because rule one of my job is that you don't trust anyone.
因为我的工作规则之一就是你不能相信任何人
If the murderer getting caught
如果凶手被抓
would expose some secrets you wouldn't want exposed,
会泄露一些你不想泄露的秘密，
we had to find out what they might be.
我们必须找出它们可能是什么
That's why we kept you in the dark.
所以我们才瞒着你
That's why we had you followed.
所以我们才会派人跟踪你
Tolga even told you
Tolga甚至告诉过你
that if you were the Nevra from the stickers,
如果你就是贴纸上的Nevra
you'd be taken off the case.
你会被调离这个案子
Why am I telling me all this now, you might ask.
我为什么现在要告诉我这一切，你可能很想知道
Because rule two of my job
因为我的工作第二条规则
is to recognize when someone's trustworthy.
就是当某人值得信赖时
Even though you knew fully well that you'd be taken off the case,
即使你很清楚你会被调离
you still didn't tamper with the evidence.
你仍然没有篡改证据
Happy birthday, by the way.
生日快乐
I assume you understand why all this subterfuge was necessary.
我想你明白为什么所有这些诡计都是必要的
As you well know,
大家都知道
this is the first killing spree of this magnitude in our country.
这是我国第一个如此大规模的屠杀案件
This is an exceptional case.
这是例外情况
It required exceptional measures.
需要采取特殊措施
You know everything now.
你现在都知道了
The choice is yours to make.
选择权在你
Both your superior and I want you on this case.
你的上司和我都想让你继续跟进案子
But if you wanted to excuse yourself, I'd understand.
但是如果你想远离这一切，我理解
Make a choice. Are you in or out?
做决定吧
- I'm in, of course. - Good.
-我当然要继续  -好
Nevra...
Nevra...
There's no more playing cowboy.
不能再随随便便了
You'll be partnering with Sefa.
你将与Sefa合作
You'll be reporting to me every day. Are we clear?
每天都要向我汇报  明白了吗？
We are, sir.
明白  先生
Shit.
该死
NEVRA AND I HAVE A SECRET
Nevra和我秘密
What were you doing here, then?
那你们在这里做什么
- Out for a picnic. - Just out for a picnic.
-野餐  -只是野餐
Out for a picnic.
野餐
Foreign-made. No one can crack it.
外国制造的  没有人能破解
Just pick a password and you're done.
只需输入密码即可
Take care not to forget the password.
注意不要忘记密码
See? They tampered with the door also.
看？他们还把门破坏了
- I can fix it if you'd like. - No need. It's fine.
-如果您愿意，我能修好它  -不用了
They broke into a house in the neighborhood.
有人闯入附近的一所房子
When they couldn't find anything to steal, they took a bath.
当他们找不到任何可以偷的东西时，他们洗了个澡
- A bath? - Yeah. Oh, and they stole some flowers.
-洗澡吗  -是的  对了  他们偷了一些花
- What would they do with flowers? - I don't know, smell them or something.
-他们偷花做什么？-我不知道  可能为了闻花香吧
Do you live alone here?
你一个人住吗？
Why do you ask?
你为什么要问？
The world isn't as innocent as it used to be back in your time.
世界不再像过去那样单纯了
What do you mean?
什么意思？
They keep tabs on old people.
他们密切关注老年人
Don't you worry about that. Old people keep tabs on them, also.
不用担心  老人们也密切注视着他们
Can I ask you a question?
我可以问你一个问题吗？
Why are the mechanics always late?
为什么修理工总是迟到？
Excuse me?
什么？
Tufan Elibol, the murder suspect in the serial killer investigation
连环杀手调查中的谋杀嫌疑人Tufan Elibol
was found dead in the back garden of famous reporter Ates Arbay's house.
被发现死于著名记者Ates Arbay的花园中
The case seems to be out of control.
该案似乎失控了
Hoping to ease the public's concerns,
为了减轻公众疑虑
the police department is planning to hold a press conference sometime today.
警察局计划今天某个时候举行新闻发布会
Do you think this has a deeper meaning? Seeing two corpses
您认为这有更深的含义吗？这两具尸体
wrapped up in cling film inside one day?
包裹在保鲜膜里？
It signals good fortunes.
象征好运
Why do you think he packages them up like this?
您为什么认为他像这样打包？
He packaged Tufan up because he was a present for me.
他把图凡包装好，因为他是我的礼物
- So he follows protocol, you think? - Sure.
-所以他是出于礼仪吗？-是的
He must not have wanted the animals to get to this one.
他一定是不想让动物吃掉这一具
Do you think he cares about what happens to the bodies?
您是否认为他关心尸体被吃掉？
No.
不是
But he does care about the messages.
但他确实关心头上的标签
He don't want something happen to them before we get the chance to read them.
在我们看到之前，他不希望发生任何事。
NEVRA AND I HAVE A SECRET
Nevra和我有个秘密
They're everywhere.
到处都有摄像头
We are gathered here to celebrate a proud giant of Turkish industry,
我们聚集在这里庆祝土耳其工业的巨人
the 73-year-old company,
这家拥有73年历史的公司
Tezgider Textiles,
特兹吉德纺织公司
merging with Havran Holding Company.
与哈夫兰控股公司合并
No... That's too long a sentence.
不，那句话太长了
- Edit it for me, will you? - Of course.
-帮我改一下吧  -好的
If Nazif isn't home, spare his life.
如果纳粹不在家，饶他一命
Who is it?
是谁呀？
I must have the wrong door, I'm sorry.
我一定是走错了，对不起
- Agah? Is that you? - Yes?
-Agah？是你吗？-是？
It's Nazif! You don't recognize me?
我是Nazif！你认不出我吗？
- Nazif? - Hold on.
-Nazif？-等等
- It's Nazif! - How's that possible?
-Nazif！-怎么可能？
Come here, you heartbreaker. Come on, come on in.
来吧 亲爱的 进来吧
Wait...
等等
It's really you, Agah! How long has it been?
真的是您，Agah！多久没见了？
Must've been twenty years. Maybe even more.
已经二十年了  可能更长
Agah...
Agah...
Darling...
亲爱的
You don't need to feel threatened.
别紧张
It's me, Nazif!
是我，Nazif！
Actually, I've been going by Naz for 16 years,
事实上，我改名为Naz已经16年了
but you can address me however you feel comfortable.
不过你叫我什么都可以
So? How's Mebrure? She's well, I hope.
Mebrure还好吗，我希望她很好
Mebrure passed away, sadly.
Mebrure不幸过世了
Ten years ago.
十年前
Oh, dear.
噢  亲爱的
May she rest in peace.
愿她安息
She was such a beautiful woman. She had a pure heart.
她是一个如此美丽的女人  她有一颗纯洁的心
Come on, take off that coat.
来脱掉那件外套
Sit back, get comfortable.
坐下来，舒服点
This is fine, Mr... Naz.
没事的，Naz先生
We don't need to call each other mister and missus.
我们之间不需要互相称呼先生和太太
That's good to hear, Naz.
这是好个消息  Naz
- My mother's passed on, as well, Agah. - May she rest in peace.
-我母亲也去世了，Agah  -愿她安息
You'd been to this house before, right?
你以前来过这所房子吧？
We came to visit you after you were assigned to Istanbul.
您被派往伊斯坦布尔后，我们来拜访过您
Yes, I remember now. I left that job, as you know.
是的，我记起来了  现在我已经退休了
I know.
我知道
We haven't seen each other since.
从那以后我们再也没有见面了
Yes, we haven't...
是的
Agah...
Agah...
Come on.
好了
Look here.
看着我
Look into my eyes.
看着我的眼睛
That's better. I'm the same person, Agah.
我还是我  Agah
I'm your old friend. Alright?
我是你的老朋友  好吗？
It's for...
这是为了……
I have a skin condition.
我有皮肤病
I have to wear a cream. Doctor's orders.
医生说必须要涂护手霜
- I hope you get better. - Thank you.
-希望你快点好起来-谢谢
Agah, I have an idea.
Agah，我有个主意
Let's have some raki!
我们吃点烤面包吧
The reporters will have a million questions.
记者将会有无数个问题
We have to get our story straight.
我们得把故事讲清楚
Nevra, wrap the case up for me.
Nevra，梳理一下案情
The last victim's name was Salih Guden. No priors. 51 years old. Truck driver.
最后一名受害者的名字是Salih Guden  51岁的卡车司机  没有前科
Nevra...
Nevra...
From the beginning.
从最开始说起
Mehmet Yurtgil. Judge. Heavy penal court.
刑事法院的Mehmet Yurtgil法官
He had a reputation for taking bribes, but we have no proof of it.
他因受贿而出名，但我们没有证据
Naimhan Turedi.
Naimhan Turedi
He's a man that sung at taverns.
他是一个酒馆里的歌手
No priors.
没有前科
But Naimhan and I share something.
但是我和Naimhan有一些共同之处
Kambura.
Kambura.
He's from Kambura. Lived there until he was 20.
他来自Kambura，一直住在那里直到20岁
My family lived in Kambura, as well.
我的家人也住在Kambura
My mom worked at the post office.
我妈妈在邮局工作
She was assigned to Kambura when I was nine.
我九岁时就被分配到Kambura
We stayed there for a year, until she was assigned to another town.
我们在那里呆了一年，直到她被分配到另一个城市
I never went back to Kambura,
我从没回过Kambura
but my mom loved that town so much that she moved there after she retired.
但是我妈妈非常喜欢那个城镇，以至于她退休后就搬到了过去
- Got married there, in fact. - You don't have to mention that.
-在那儿结婚  -您不必说这些
And then, there's Tufan.
然后是Tufan
Tufan has no connection whatsoever to Kambura.
Tufan与Kambura没有任何联系
However, three days before Mehmet Yurtgil was killed,
但是，在Mehmet Yurtgil法官被杀之前三天，
the Ardıchan Courthouse was burned down.
Ardıchan法院大楼被烧毁
That's where he got the guns.
那是他拿到枪的地方
He also took whatever illegal items he could find in the evidence locker.
他还带走了他在证据柜里能找到的所有非法物品
He could be in possession of drugs and explosives.
他可能拥有毒品和爆炸物
We're still waiting on the inventory list to know exactly what he took.
我们还在等着看他到底有什么东西
Why the Ardıchan Courthouse?
为什么选择Ardıchan法院大楼？
I can't wrap my head around that. Why not another courthouse but that one?
我无法理解  为什么不是另一个法院而是那个呢?
Nevermind. Keep going.
没关系  继续
He also took the case files in the courthouse.
他还带走了法院案卷
He needed someone to pin the murders on.
他需要有人来顶罪
He had to be someone with a record
必须是一个有前科的人
so that we'd quickly identify him as the killer,
以便我们能够迅速将他确定为杀手，
buying the real killer time to commit the other murders.
为真正的杀手赢得时间去实施其他的谋杀
He found Tufan from those case files. An ex-con jailed for killing his wife.
他从这些案卷中找到了Tufan  一名前诈骗犯  因杀害妻子而入狱
He probably kidnapped Tufan after burning down the courthouse,
他可能在烧毁法院后绑架了Tufan
and planted his fingerprints on the stickers.
把他的指纹贴在贴纸上
By the way...
顺便说一下
The stickers and the card we found on Tufan bore no fingerprints.
我们在Tufan尸体的贴纸上没有发现指纹
- Now, this heavy penal judge... - Mehmet Yurtgil.
-那么这位刑事法官  -Mehmet Yurtgil.
Yes.
是的
Does he have any connections to Kambura?
他和Kambura有任何联系吗？
No, sir. At least none we've found so far.
没有，先生，到目前为止我们至少没有找到
How about the third victim, Salih Guden, the truck driver?
第三位受害者  卡车司机Salih Guden呢？
He's not from Kambura,
他不是来自坎布拉
but he's been going there for work for years. So yes, he might.
但他已经去那里工作了多年了，所以，他可能有联系
Alright, then.
那好吧
Three victims. Scratch Tufan. Two of them are from Kambura.
除去Tufan之外  三名受害者其中两人来自Kambura
You've lived in Kambura for a while. That counts as a lead, don't you think?
你已经在坎布拉住了一段时间了  那算是个线索，对吗？
So all this does have something to do with Kambura.
所以这一切都与Kambura有关
But why did he let Tufan go?
但是为什么他杀死了Tufan？
Why did he want us to find Tufan?
他为什么要我们找到Tufan？
That must be Timur. He's doing the autopsy on Tufan.
一定是Timur  他正在对Tufan做尸检
- Do you have anything, Timur? - The whole body was soaked in bleach.
-发现什么了吗，Timur？-整个身体都被漂白剂浸透过了
No traces of DNA on him.
他身上没有DNA的痕迹
But he does have soft tissue trauma on his wrists and ankles.
但是他的手腕和脚踝有软组织创伤
He was kept tied up for a prolonged time.
他被绑了很长时间
And I don't know if it means anything, but they fed him cat food.
我不知道这是否意味着什么，但他们喂猫粮给他吃
I found cat food in his stomach.
我发现他肚子里有猫食
SUSPECT
嫌犯
How is this possible?
这怎么可能？
I really had no idea.
我真的不知道
I did everything I could to keep it from you guys.
我尽我所能不让你们知道
You've been with women before, haven't you?
你以前和女人交往过，是吗?
I have. It's really hard not to doubt your true feeling.
我有  但很难不去怀疑真实的感受
It's so scary, it feels like your whole world might come down.
太可怕了  感觉好像你的整个世界都要塌下来了
That's why I always tried to convince myself
这就是为什么我一直试图说服自己
that what I was feeling wasn't real.
我的感觉不是真实的
It's a way of deceiving yourself, really.
这是一种欺骗自己的方法，真的
I went to bed with so many women just to prove myself to others.
我和很多女人上床只是为了向别人证明自己
It's not like I was able to have sex with any of them, though.
但我又不能和任何人上床
There was this one girl...
有一个女孩
She was beautiful. I can't remember her name. Whatever.
她很漂亮  我不记得她的名字了
That bastard Sungur used to pimp them out, remember?
那个混蛋Sungur曾经给她拉皮条，还记得吗？
I do.
我记得
She cried. The thought of me not liking her was devastating for her.
她哭了，一想到我不喜欢她，她就受不了
She thought I'd go back to Sungur and tell him I didn't like her.
她以为我会回去告诉Sungur我不喜欢她
She was scared he'd beat her up.
她很害怕他会殴打她
Actually, when I think back...
其实我回想起来
She was the first person I ever told.
她是我曾经告诉过的第一个人
She was the first person I confessed to.
她是我第一个坦白的人
I told her I didn't really like women.
我告诉她我不是很喜欢女人
That's all I have for you. My story ends there.
这就是我的故事了
Time to tell yours.
是时候讲讲你的故事
What brings you to my home?
你怎么来这里了？
Nazif...
Nazif...
I'm sorry, Naz...
抱歉，Naz
You say it so beautifully!
你说得真好听！
Say my name again.
再说一次我的名字
Naz...
Naz
- Yes, dear? - I'm sick.
-怎么了，亲爱的--我病了
Early stages of Alzheimer's.
早期阿尔茨海默氏症
Sadly... I'll forget everything.
可悲的是我会忘记一切
Everything.
一切
So I told myself...
所以我告诉自己
That before I forgot...
在我忘记之前
I should visit my old friends.
我应该去拜访我的老朋友
- Oh, dear. - Yeah.
-天啊  -是的
Oh, darling.
亲爱的
Agah...
Agah...
You know what we're going to do now?
你知道我们现在要做什么吗？
Do you remember that night when we got drunk
你还记得那天晚上我们喝醉了吗
and wrote a song together?
一起写歌
Yes?
嗯？
- I still have it on paper. - No way.
-我还留着呢  -不会吧
See?
你看
That's really something. It was in the key of Segah?
真了不起  那是Segah的琴键吗
No, not Segah!
不，不是Segah！
Agah...
Agah...
It's in the key of Agah.
在Agah的琴键上
I have the oud right here.
我这里有乌德琴
No more nightingales No more roses.
没有更多的夜莺  没有更多的玫瑰
The pain inside Is all I have
内心充满了痛苦
I can't go on Any longer.
我不能再继续了
Oh, lover, lover, Please end me.
哦，爱人，爱人，请终结我
Ah...
啊
Alas...
唉
In the key of Agah...
在Agah的琴键上
I wasted my life...
我浪费了生命
I've gone mad!
我发疯了！
Gone mad!
疯了！
- We used to have so much fun. - Those were the days.
-我们曾经有过很多欢乐  -那些日子
We used to recite poems. From Nazım, from Yahya Kemal...
我们曾经背诵Nazım，Yahya Kemal的诗
- Cheers to those days, Agah. - Cheers to young times past.
-为那段日子欢呼  -过去的岁月欢呼
Shut up! We're still young!
闭嘴！我们还年轻！
Sure we are. How many glasses does this make?
当然，这是第几杯了？
I'm pretty drunk.
我好醉
I haven't seen you for ages. Stop whining!
我好久没见到你了！别抱怨
You know what I thought?
你知道我的想法吗？
I thought that once I became a woman,
我以为一旦成为​​女人
all my troubles would go away. I'd finally be happy.
我所有的烦恼都会消失  最终会很高兴
I did become happy.
我确实变得快乐
But I'd forgotten about a detail.
但是我忘了一个细节
Something was missing, Agah.
有些东西不见了，Agah
You can't live without love.
你不能活在没有爱的世界中
Nothing works when you don't have love.
当你没有爱时  什么都不能做
Without love,
没有爱，
no more nightingales...
没有更多的夜莺
No more roses.
没有更多的玫瑰
I'm so unhappy, Agah!
我很难过，Agah！
I'm so alone!
我好寂寞！
No one's knocked on that door for years!
多年来没有人敲过那扇门！
But I don't care! I still dress up every night!
但是我不在乎，我仍然每晚都打扮！
It works, you see? You finally came!
终于奏效了，您终于来了！
It was so good of you to come!
你来这里我真的很高兴
Maybe you didn't come to say goodbye.
也许你不是来说再见
Maybe you came to say hello!
也许你来打个招呼！
A little birdie told me...
一只小鸟告诉我
That there's something about your past that you just can't shake.
你无法摆脱你过去的某些东西
Might that be me?
可能是我吗？
You have a drop...
你有一滴
of raki right there.
葡萄酒在那里
Let me drink my fill.
让我喝个够
Whose poem is that?
那是谁的诗？
Mine.
我的
For you.
为你而作
Agah...
Agah
What the...
什么
Shit!
该死！
What's this?
这是什么？
What did you do, Agah?
你做了什么，阿加？
What did you do!
你做了什么！
Die, you bastard!
去死吧，你这个混蛋！
Come here!
过来！
Don't!
别！
Don't hurt the instrument!
别打坏乐器！
Don't! Don't!
不要！不要！
Don't!
别！
Don't...
别
I'll show you!
去死吧！
That's all the information I have for you. I have summed up the situation for now.
这就是所有的信息  我已经总结了一下现在的情况
We will keep sharing our information with the public in the coming days.
未来几天我们将继续与公众分享我们的信息
Lastly, for our citizens who live in Istanbul's immediate vicinity,
最后，对于住在伊斯坦布尔附近的公民来说，
there's no reason to panic. We are on the case.
没有理由惊慌  我们正在处理这起案件
Chiefly the Murder Bureau,
虽然主要是凶杀科
but in fact the whole police force,
但实际上整个警察部队
is working to solve the murders and bring swift justice on the murderer.
都正在努力解决谋杀案  并迅速将凶手绳之以法
Our citizens can rest easy.
我们的公民可以安心
Whoever it is that is committing these murders
无论是谁犯下这些谋杀案
will soon be caught and tried.
很快就会被抓住
You don't need to doubt that.
您不必怀疑
I'll be taking questions shortly,
我很快就能回答大家的提问
but since the case, as you know, involves sensitive information,
但是，正如您所知，这种情况涉及敏感信息，
I might have to refrain from answering some of your questions.
我可能不得不避免回答您的一些问题
I ask for your understanding.
敬请谅解
Sir! Sir!
先生  先生
- Go ahead. - Does the cat costume signify anything?
-继续  -扮成猫有什么特殊含义吗？
- Do you think it might be a message? - He's definitely an animal lover.
-你认为这可能是个线索吗？-他绝对很喜欢动物
But as you all know, Hitler was in love with his dogs. Any other questions?
但是众所周知，希特勒爱上了他的狗  还有其他问题吗？
You do realize!
你知道！
That you've been up there for an hour without saying anything.
你已经在那里呆了一个小时没说有用的话
Four people were killed inside a single week.
一个星期内有四人被杀
People are scared to leave their homes.
人们由于害怕而离开家乡
And all you have to say...
而你却只能说……
To allay their fears...
为了减轻公众的恐惧
Is that you're working on it.
你正在处理了
As all the reporters gathered here and the millions watching on TV know,
所有聚集在这里的记者和数百万电视观众都知道
a government official saying he's working on it
一名政府官员说他正在处理
means they are not doing anything.
表示他们什么也没做
If you were making any real progress, you'd have shared that with us.
如果您正在取得任何实际进展，请与我们分享
You have nothing to show for your efforts.
你的努力没有任何成果
Ates Arbay, right?
Ates Arbay，对不对？
Are you done?
你说完了吗？
Good.
好
Gathered here...
大家聚集在这里
are countless reporters with spotless records.
有数不清的记者有着一尘不染的记录
I will defer to them on the legitimacy of your work.
我将尊重他们对你工作合法性的看法
But I condemn you for your words that defame me and my department.
但我谴责您诽谤我和我部门的言论
Do you really not have anything?
你真的什么都没有吗？
Don't you have any leads?
你没有线索吗？
Please calm down! I get it, you're concerned.
请冷静一下！我明白你们担心什么
And you have a right to be.
你有权利这样做
That's why I'll be sharing another information with you.
这就是为什么我要与您分享其他信息的原因
The murder suspect used Tufan Elibol to throw us off his trail.
谋杀嫌疑犯利用Tufan Elibol来摆脱我们的追踪
But Tufan Elibol's body contained useful evidence.
但是Tufan Elibol的尸体包含了有用的证据
You made me do it, Agah!
你逼我的，Agah！
Tufan Elibol, whom the killer used to throw us off his scent
Tufan Elibol，凶手曾经用他来迷惑我们
will prove instrumental in the killer getting caught.
将对杀手的抓捕有帮助
The killer has made his bed.
凶手已经插翅难逃
A bomb goes off, killing 50 people, and you don't panic.
炸弹爆炸，炸死50人，你没有惊慌
But when people are picked off one by one, then you do. Is that it?
但是，当人们被一个人接一个杀掉的时候，你就惊慌了吗？
One thing we know is that the killer doesn't torture his victims, right?
我们确定的是杀人犯不会折磨受害者，对吗？
He hasn't so far, yes.
到目前为止还没有
We're over here, dad!
爸爸，我们在这里！
- Cemil? - Look who I've brought.
-Cemil？-看看我带来了谁
- I told you he'd recognize me. - Come here!
-我告诉过你他会认出我 -过来！
I see you all over on TV, in newspapers. Of course I recognized you.
我在电视，报纸上到处都能见到你  我当然能认出你
- You're truly your own man now! - You haven't changed a bit!
-你现在真的是自己的人了 -你没变！
- I'm getting old. - I won't hear it. You look incredible!
-我变老了  -我假装没听见  你看起来好极了
Come on. I'm getting old.
我变老了
How do you know each other?
你们怎么认识的？
I've met Zuhal really recently. As of today, she works for me.
我最近才见到Zuhal   从今天开始  她为我工作
You didn't tell me.
你没告诉我
I really love him, you know. I knew him as a child, back in Kambura.
我真的很爱他，你知道我很小的时候就认识他
Such a nice surprise!
真是个惊喜！
- Hi, by the way. - Hi.
-嗨，顺便说一句  -嗨
So? How are you doing, Cemil?
你好吗，Cemil？
He seems to exhibit
他似乎没有表现出
none of the obsessions and sexual fantasies of serial killers.
连环杀手的偏执和性幻想
We don't know whether he enjoys the act of killing or not.
我们不知道他是否喜欢杀人
He seems to be a simple murderer.
他似乎是一个很简单的凶手
They usually have only two motives: Either money or revenge.
他们通常只有两个动机：金钱或报仇
Since he's never stolen anything, he must be after revenge.
既然他从未拿取财物，那么他一定是想报仇
He has so many people to take revenge on that it turns him into a serial killer.
他要找很多人报仇，这使他成为连环杀手
Not just three or four people.
不只是三四个人
Maybe ten...
可能有10个
Maybe 20.
也许20个
Maybe even more.
甚至更多
And then there're the messages.
然后有消息
All meant for me.
都是为了我
I mean...
我的意思是
He leaves clues for the police.
他为警察留下了线索
But why?
但为什么？
Why does he do it?
他为什么要这样做？
Ten years ago, a crowd, I don't know how many people yet,
十年前，有一群人，我不知道有多少人，
gathered outside this house and burned it to the ground.
聚集在这所房子外面，并烧毁了它
How did you find out about this? Who told you?
您是怎么知道的？谁告诉您的？
Selim, my mom's current husband told me.
我妈妈的现任丈夫Selim告诉我的
He was here too, sadly.
可悲的是他曾经也在这里
Selim says that a single person threw the torch,
Selim说，有一个人把火把扔了进去
but he never saw who.
但他没看到是谁
But from what I gather, no one ran in to help the people inside.
但据我所知，没有人进去帮助里面的人
That night, seven people died in the fire.
那天晚上，七人在大火中丧生
A mother, a father, and five children.
一位母亲，一位父亲和五个孩子
And most importantly, at least according to Selim,
最重要的是，至少根据塞利姆所说
one of the victims was in the crowd that night.
那天晚上其中一名受害者就在人群中
Naimhan.
Naimhan
The man you told me about,
你跟我说过的那个人
the one you chased all the way here...
你一直在这里寻找的那个人
- You never saw his face? - No, I couldn't!
-你没看过他的脸吗？-不，我看不到！
It was dark.
当时太黑了
I never saw his face, but I'm certain that he wanted to bring me here.
我没见过他的脸，但我确定他想把我带到这里
He brought me here, and asked me to remember.
他把我带到这里，要我记住
I've been here for three years. This is the first I'm hearing of this.
我在这里三年了  这是我第一次听说
That's strange. You never wondered why and how it happened?
真奇怪，你从来没想过为什么会这样吗？
No.
没有
Good for you.
真不错
Turn on the computer. I want to take a look at the archives.
打开电脑  我想看看档案
Um...
嗯
Um?
嗯？
The archives are in here.
档案在这里
What have you been doing for the past three years?
过去三年来你一直在做什么？
Waiting to get assigned to another town.
等待分配到另一个城镇
Go wait over there, then. Come on in, Nevra.
去那边等一下，过来  Nevra
I don't believe it.
难以置信
He's such a humble man.
他是一个谦虚的人
We've been talking for hours, and he hasn't mentioned
我们已经聊了好几个小时，他从没提到过
all he's done even once.
他曾经做过的一切
What have I done?
我做了什么？
Don't be coy.
别害羞
I was orphaned at the age of nine, Zuhal.
我九岁就是孤儿了，Zuhal
My father died suddenly.
我父亲突然去世了
My mother was a wretch.
我母亲是个不幸的人
She was always sick, too. We were left all alone.
她也总是生病，让我们一个人呆着
You know who took care of us?
你知道谁照顾我们吗？
Kambura did.
Kambura照顾我们
Kamburans.
Kambura的人们
They bought me school supplies.
他们给我买了学习用品
They dressed me.
给我衣服穿
Even the poorest among them found a way to get my mom some money.
即使是他们中最穷的人也能找到办法给我妈妈弄点钱
They all wanted me to become learned. So I did.
他们都希望我学习知识，所以我做到了
I could've never come to Istanbul to go to college if it weren't for them.
如果不是他们的话，我绝对不会来伊斯坦布尔上大学
And your father here,
还有你的父亲
paid for a tutor for me,
为我付了家教费
even though he was just a civil servant.
虽然他只是一个公务员
You paid for my tutor year after year.
你年复一年地为我的导师付费
Come on, forget about it.
好了，别说了
- Anyone would've done the same. - No.
-任何人都会做相同的事 -不
I've never forgotten, Agah.
我从未忘记，Agah
I owe a lot to Kambura and to you.
我要归功于Kambura和你
You don't owe anyone anything.
你什么都不欠我的
You can't imagine how happy I was when I found out that Zuhal was your daughter.
你无法想象我发现Zuhal是你的女儿时我有多高兴
But I'm telling you now, with Zuhal as my witness,
但是我现在以Zuhal为证人告诉你，
that if you need anything at all, I want you to tell me about it.
如果您需要任何帮助，我希望您告诉我
I'll be deeply hurt if you don't.
如果你不这样做，我会很伤心的
Sure. Of course. I will.
当然会的
I'm serious. You know I mean it.
我很认真  你知道我是认真的
I know.
我知道
You're a good man.
你是好人
You were back then,
你在那时是好人
and you still are.
现在也是
KILL
杀
Nevra, I found it.
Nevra，我找到了
What?
什么？
You have the reports?
你有报告吗？
Nevra, no one burned it down.
Nevra，没人烧毁它
What do you mean, no one did?
什么意思，没人？
Here's the report. The cause for the fire was a cigarette.
这是报告  起火的原因是香烟
There were two gas lamps inside the house. That's why the fire grew out of control.
屋子里有两个煤气灯，这就是大火失控的原因
But there was a crowd gathered outside.
但是外面有一群人
Yes, they did. It's written in the police report.
是的 警方报告是这样的：
"The locals gathered around the house"
“当地人聚集在房子周围
and did their best to control the fire before the fire department arrived.
在消防部门到达之前尽了最大的努力来控制火势
However, despite the locals' efforts,
但是，尽管有当地人的努力，
the seven people inside the house, probably asleep at the time,
屋子里的七个人，当时大概睡着了，
"were unable to be rescued alive."
无法被救出”
Nevra, those people didn't gather there to start a fire.
内夫拉，那些人没有聚集在那里放火
They gathered there to rescue the ones inside.
他们聚集在那里是要救出里面的人
But Selim told me otherwise.
但是塞利姆告诉我的不一样
He was there. He saw it with his own eyes.
他在那里  亲眼所见
No. I wasn't there at the time.
不，我当时不在
But Selim,
可是Selim
you told me you threw a stone at the house.
你告诉我的  你朝房子扔石头
You told me it haunted your dreams.
你告诉我它萦绕在我的梦中
Exactly. It's nothing but a dream.
只是梦而已
He confuses them with reality.
他混淆了梦和现实
He goes off the rails when he neglects his meds.
他不按时服药就会这样
They came all the way from Istanbul hoping to find something.
他们大老远从伊斯坦布尔赶来，希望发现一些线索
You should be more thoughtful.
你应该多考虑一下
Sugar?
Sugar?